<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Evnir</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Evnir_(5e_Race)">DandD Wiki: Homebrew</author>
		<update version="0.1.9">
			<file name="race-evnir.xml" url="" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Evnir" type="Race" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACE_EVNIR">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">“Do you know where they came from?” Sigmund said as he watched the small group of Evnir headed off down the road to the next town.<br />
			The other merchant shrugged, “Never seen anything like it. Mechanical beings that act just like humans... think they'll be back?” <br />
			Kien smirked, “Why? One of them strikes your fancy already?”<br />
			“No! … Alright maybe, but that's beside the point. If they get this trade route set up, think of what it'd mean for the town. No one else has bothered to help us, why would they?”<br />Kien shrugged going back into the shop as he spoke, “Maybe they want to fit in? Now c'mon Sigmund, your metal girlfriend will come back. We still have work to do.”<br />
			Sigmund followed after rolling his eyes, “She'd probably be easier to woo than that orc you went after last month...”</p>
			<h4>Physical Description</h4>
			<p>Evnir appear to be finely crafted mechanical beings that closely resemble humans in appearance aside from some noticeable details. Their 'skin' appears to be a pale white color, balled joints making up all of their joints, but fitting into the plates that make up their arms, legs, and body almost seamlessly with very little room, if any, for anything to get inside of the joint. </p>
			<p class="indent">They have artificial hair that ranges in style and length, though the color always has a metallic tone to it often shimmering in bright light. An Evnir's eyes appear to be normal at a casual glance, but closer inspection reveals that the inner working of their eyes are carefully made mechanical irises with each Evnir having a unique color. Every Evnir has a winding key that sits in the middle of their back akin to a wind-up toy and every winding key on each Evnir is unique with each of the keys having elaborate designs on them and the key only being able to fit into the Evnir it was designed for. The keys are normally only made of common metals, with the rare metals only appearing very rarely on specific Evnir</p>
			<p class="indent">Every Evnir has a winding key that sits in the middle of their back akin to a wind-up toy and every winding key on each Evnir is unique with each of the keys having elaborate designs on them and the key only being able to fit into the Evnir it was designed for. The keys are normally only made of common metals, with the rare metals only appearing very rarely on specific Evnir</p>
			<p class="indent">Evnir only difference in gender comes from the difference in their external body structure with the 'males' tending to be taller with larger chest cavities and 'females' being smaller with slimmer frames though no less capable than their counterparts. Evnir do not distinguish themselves as male or female, although when others do distinguish them as a particular 'gender', an Evnir will usually go along with it, curious to understand the difference or what being part of such gender means.</p>
			<p class="indent">An Evnir's voice has a distinct metallic ringing sound to it. Their voices vary in pitch and tone, with the ringing matching the pitch of their voice and usually comes off as a pleasant accompanying sound with their speech, though this makes it difficult for them to mimic other people's voices.</p>
			<h4>History</h4>
			<p>Evnir come from an unknown place, made by an unknown creator. Every time they appear, it is almost always from an underground cave or other hidden areas, with all of them becoming active at the same time. The number of them that 'come to life' varies but once they are introduced into an area, it's very rare to ever see any new Evnir appear. After activation, they're fully aware of themselves and begin to investigate their surroundings and determine what it is they need to do next. </p>
			<p class="indent">Most of them traveling in small groups and expanding out from where they've awoken and trying to introduce and integrate themselves into the society that they've found themselves in. They're typically non-violent, only resorting to violence when necessary to protect themselves or those who they've grown to care for. Although they're also known for their love of adventure and exploring, not ever hesitating to venture out into the world and discover everything they can.</p>
			<h4>Society</h4>
			<p>Evnir have no specific homeland of their own, because of this they tend to integrate themselves into whatever society they find nearby, almost going out of their way to ingratiate themselves with locals to ensure that they can survive in the environment they find themselves in. They don't discriminate among who they meet either, enjoying talking and learning about any race they come across, usually asking if they need any assistance so that they can gain a people's trust.</p>
			<h4>EVNIR NAMES</h4>
			<p>Evnir have no set naming conventions, deciding among themselves what they feel fits for themselves after they've been activated.</p>
			<p class="indent">Their information on how they name themselves, they believe, was preset into them before they were activated and Evnir has speculated that their ideas for naming themselves come from whatever their creator was and what names they liked. Collectively they decide what their 'surname' will be, most surnames they choose will be closely related to a metal.</p>
			<p>
			<span class="feature">Male Names:</span> Tonrec, Joslil, Daero, Kasver, Garrus, Theren, Felver, Corvon, Sedar, Yeros<br />
			<span class="feature">Female Names:</span>Nua, Seldra, Aradi, Isonoa, Kattyn, Encyne, Ceri, Keldrey, Elinvar, Orla<br />
			<span class="feature">Surnames:</span>Stellus, Ironun, Tinure, Copperia, Silvey, Lithi, Caesi, Radis, Vanad, Galli
			</p>
			<h4>EVNIR TRAITS</h4>
			<p>A clockwork race of unknown origins, even to themselves.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Constitution score increases by 2.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Evnir are all 'activated' at the same time and are considered adults at such time. They live on average of 200 years but can last as long as 600 years if meticulously maintained and upgraded.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Most Evnir tend towards good or neutral alignments, wanting to integrate and blend into the societies of the people they meet with.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Evnir range from 5-6 feet in height. Your size is Medium.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet. You sink in water as if your speed was 0 and you were falling.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>A Machine's Toolkit.</em></strong> You gain proficiency with a set artisan's tools of your choice.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Living Construct.</em></strong> Even though you were constructed, you are a living creature. Your creature type is both construct and humanoid. You are immune to diseases and being poisoned. You do not need to eat or breathe, but you can ingest food and drink if you wish. Instead of sleeping, an Evnir needs to wind the key that is in its back along with performing regular maintenance on their body this takes 4 hours each day. You are fully aware of your surroundings and notice approaching enemies and other events as normal. An Evnir can go a number of days without winding their key equal to their proficiency bonus, if they fail to wind their key after a number of days equal to their proficiency bonus then they fall unconscious until their key is wound back up. In addition, instead of a Wisdom (Medicine) check a Intelligence check or an Intelligence (Tinker's Tools) check is needed to stabilize you.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Flexible.</em></strong> You can take the Dodge action as a bonus action a number of times equal to your Dexterity modifier(minimum 1). You regain all expanded uses of this trait when you complete a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sounds of Gears.</em></strong> The subtle sound of moving gears, springs and other mechanical components surround you, causing you to have disadvantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Mendable.</em></strong>When the mending spell is cast on you and you have 0 hit points you become stable. Alternatively, as part of the casting of mending, the caster may expend one of their spell slots, causing you to regain a number of hit points equal to 1d8 + their spellcasting ability modifier; when this is done using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Subrace.</em></strong> Evnir's internal construction tend to lean towards specific abilities. As to whether or not Evnir actually follow their internal makeup is entirely up to them, though if they do, they find themselves able to perform above what would be considered the average.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male">Tonrec, Joslil, Daero, Kasver, Garrus, Theren, Felver, Corvon, Sedar, Yeros</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Nua, Seldra, Aradi, Isonoa, Kattyn, Encyne, Ceri, Keldrey, Elinvar, Orla</set>
			<set name="names" type="family">Stellus, Ironun, Tinure, Copperia, Silvey, Lithi, Caesi, Radis, Vanad, Galli</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}} {{family}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d10">4'6"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="1d4">300 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="constitution" value="2" requirements="!ID_UA_PSK_GRANTS_EVNIR_SUBRACE" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="speed:swim" value="0" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MACH_TOOLKIT" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_CONSTRUCT" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_FLEXIBLE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SOUND_OF_GEARS" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MENDABLE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_EVNIR_SUBRACE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="A Machine's Toolkit" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MACH_TOOLKIT">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with a set artisan's tools of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You have proficiency in a set of artisan's tools.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Artisan Tool, Evnir" supports="Artisan tools" requirements="!ID_RACE_EVNIR" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Living Construct" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIVING_CONSTRUCT">
		<description>
			<p>Even though you were constructed, you are a living creature. Your creature type is both construct and humanoid. You are immune to diseases and being poisoned. You do not need to eat or breathe, but you can ingest food and drink if you wish. Instead of sleeping, an Evnir needs to wind the key that is in its back along with performing regular maintenance on their body this takes 4 hours each day. You are fully aware of your surroundings and notice approaching enemies and other events as normal. An Evnir can go a number of days without winding their key equal to their proficiency bonus, if they fail to wind their key after a number of days equal to their proficiency bonus then they fall unconscious until their key is wound back up. In addition, instead of a Wisdom (Medicine) check a Intelligence check or an Intelligence (Tinker's Tools) check is needed to stabilize you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Immune to: Disease and Poisoned. You can eat food and drink if you wish, but do not need to. You do not need to sleep, you need to wind your key and perform regular maintenance (4 hours) each day. You are fully aware of your surroundings and notice approaching enemies and other events as normal. You can go a number of days equal to your proficiency bonus without winding your key. If you do not wind key, you fall unconscious until key is wound.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Flexible" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_FLEXIBLE">
		<description>
			<p>You can take the Dodge action as a bonus action a number of times equal to your Dexterity modifier(minimum 1). You regain all expanded uses of this trait when you complete a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Evnir can take the Dodge action as a bonus action a number of times equal to Dexterity modifier(minimum 1). Regain expended uses after a long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Sound of Gears" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SOUND_OF_GEARS">
		<description>
			<p>The subtle sound of moving gears, springs and other mechanical components surround you, causing you to have disadvantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Evnir can take the Dodge action as a bonus action a number of times equal to Dexterity modifier(minimum 1). Regain expended uses after a long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mendable" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MENDABLE">
		<description>
			<p>When the mending spell is cast on you and you have 0 hit points you become stable. Alternatively, as part of the casting of mending, the caster may expend one of their spell slots, causing you to regain a number of hit points equal to 1d8 + their spellcasting ability modifier; when this is done using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Elves don’t need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Elven Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_EVNIR_SUBRACE">
		<description>
			<p>Evnir's internal construction tend to lean towards specific abilities. As to whether or not Evnir actually follow their internal makeup is entirely up to them, though if they do, they find themselves able to perform above what would be considered the average.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Sub Race" name="Evnir Subrace" supports="Evnir" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Mechanic" type="Sub Race" source="Homebrew" id="ID_SUB_RACE_MECHANIC">
		<supports>Evnir</supports>
		<description>
			<p>These Evnir are more skilled with their hands than the rest, able to work on all various types of things, from forging to sewing they manipulate things with precision and skill that would normally come from years of practice. Mechanics tend to be more reserved and quiet, not venturing too far from towns or their own shops. Some are known to want to experience the world they're placed in, eager to see just how much they can find and create throughout the land.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Intelligence score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Creator.</em></strong> You have proficiency with Tinker's tools. Using those tools, you can spend 1 hour and 20gp worth of materials you can construct a Tiny clockwork device that serves a specific, simple function. They have an Armor Class of 6 and 2 hit points. The device ceases to function after 24 hours (unless you spend 1 hour repairing it to keep the device functioning), or when you use your action to dismantle it; at that time, you can reclaim the materials used to create it. You can have up to three such devices active at a time.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Creator: Messenger.</em></strong> These constructs are kept small to be discreet, allowing them to travel unseen and deliver messages to whomever they were assigned to without being noticed. The message they carry can either be vocal or written, depending on the situation and once the message is delivered, and the recipient confirms they heard it, it immediately returns to its creator. This device has a walking speed of 10 feet and a flying speed of 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Creator: Delivery.</em></strong> Usually made into the form of small animals or basic, bipedal machines with a compartment for holding whatever needs to be delivered. Once the parcel is received by its recipient it will return to its creator and it will only take a couple hours to reset it if a new destination is needed. It has no real means of defense only able to escape any attackers by its agility. This device has a walking speed of 40 feet and a +2 to all Dexterity saving throws.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="height" modifier="1d20">4'6"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="1d4">300 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="constitution" value="1" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_CREATOR" />
		</rules>
	</element> 	
	<element name="Creator" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_CREATOR">
		<description>
			<p>You have proficiency with Tinker's tools. Using those tools, you can spend 1 hour and 20gp worth of materials you can construct a Tiny clockwork device that serves a specific, simple function. They have an Armor Class of 6 and 2 hit points. The device ceases to function after 24 hours (unless you spend 1 hour repairing it to keep the device functioning), or when you use your action to dismantle it; at that time, you can reclaim the materials used to create it. You can have up to three such devices active at a time.</p>
			<p class="indent">Messenger- These constructs are kept small to be discreet, allowing them to travel unseen and deliver messages to whomever they were assigned to without being noticed. The message they carry can either be vocal or written, depending on the situation and once the message is delivered, and the recipient confirms they heard it, it immediately returns to its creator. This device has a walking speed of 10 feet and a flying speed of 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">Delivery- Usually made into the form of small animals or basic, bipedal machines with a compartment for holding whatever needs to be delivered. Once the parcel is received by its recipient it will return to its creator and it will only take a couple hours to reset it if a new destination is needed. It has no real means of defense only able to escape any attackers by its agility. This device has a walking speed of 40 feet and a +2 to all Dexterity saving throws.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="true">
			<description><p>You have proficiency with Tinker's tools. Using those tools, you can spend 1 hour and 20gp worth of materials you can construct a Tiny clockwork device that serves a specific, simple function. They have an Armor Class of 6 and 2 hit points. The device ceases to function after 24 hours (unless you spend 1 hour repairing it to keep the device functioning), or when you use your action to dismantle it; at that time, you can reclaim the materials used to create it. You can have up to three such devices active at a time.</p>
			<p class="indent">Messenger- These constructs are kept small to be discreet, allowing them to travel unseen and deliver messages to whomever they were assigned to without being noticed. The message they carry can either be vocal or written, depending on the situation and once the message is delivered, and the recipient confirms they heard it, it immediately returns to its creator. This device has a walking speed of 10 feet and a flying speed of 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">Delivery- Usually made into the form of small animals or basic, bipedal machines with a compartment for holding whatever needs to be delivered. Once the parcel is received by its recipient it will return to its creator and it will only take a couple hours to reset it if a new destination is needed. It has no real means of defense only able to escape any attackers by its agility. This device has a walking speed of 40 feet and a +2 to all Dexterity saving throws.</p></description>
		</sheet>
		
	</element>
	<element name="Cantrip" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_CANTRIP">
		<description>
			<p>You know one cantrip of your choice from the wizard spell list. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for it.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You know one cantrip of your choice from the wizard spell list. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for it.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Spell" name="Wizard Cantrip (High Elf)" supports="Wizard&amp;&amp;0" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Extra Language" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_EXTRA_LANGUAGE">
		<description>
			<p>You can speak, read, and write one extra language of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Elf)" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Trader" type="Sub Race" source="Homebrew" id="ID_SUB_RACE_TRADER">
		<supports>Evnir</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Trader Evnir are well known for their ability to socialize more than anything else. They're more friendly than any other Evnir and will engage any and everyone they meet, trying to talk their way into, or out of, any situation they come across. They quickly become knowledgeable in local customs and traditions and love meeting new people to learn what they can from them about the area. Traders also have an excellent sense of direction, never losing their way, be it on a mountain, a dense forest or an open field.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Wisdom score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>A Way With Words.</em></strong> Whenever you make an Charisma (Persuasion) check attempting to barter, trade or engage in some other commerce based activity, you are considered proficient in the Persuasion skill and add double your proficiency bonus to the check, instead of your normal proficiency bonus.</p>
					</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="height" modifier="1d20">4'6"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="1d4">300 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_WAY_WITH_WORDS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="A Way With Words" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_WAY_WITH_WORDS">
		<description>
			<p>Whenever you make an Charisma (Persuasion) check attempting to barter, trade or engage in some other commerce based activity, you are considered proficient in the Persuasion skill and add double your proficiency bonus to the check, instead of your normal proficiency bonus.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You have double proficiency on Persuasion checks while engaged in commerce-based activity.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="persuasion:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" alt="Double Proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Soldier" type="Sub Race" source="Homebrew" id="ID_SUB_RACE_SOLDIER">
		<supports>Evnir</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Soldier Evnir are the only Evnir that look physically different in appearance, their normally pale, white skin is instead deep silver color. Their skin doesn't seem to be any thicker than other Evnir, although it does seem to have a better resistance to it than other Evnir. </p>
			<p class="indent">They're more formal and less talkative than most other Evnir, but only to other races. They're friendly with members of their own race, but can be a bit on the protective side when others approach their group.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Silver Skinned.</em></strong> While unarmored, your Armor Class is equal to 13 + your Dexterity modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</p>
			
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="height" modifier="1d20">4'6"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="1d6">300 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="1" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SILVER_SKINNED" />
			</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Silver Skinned" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SILVER_SKINNED">
		<description>
			<p>While unarmored, your Armor Class is equal to 13 + your Dexterity modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</p></description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While unarmored, your Armor Class is equal to 13 + your Dexterity modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:silvered skin soldier:base" value="13" />
			<stat name="ac:silvered skin soldier:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:silvered skin soldier" value="ac:silvered skin soldier:base" />
			<stat name="ac:silvered skin soldier" value="ac:silvered skin soldier:dexterity" />
			
			<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:silvered skin soldier" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Silvered Skin (Soldier)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
		<element name="Scholar" type="Sub Race" source="Homebrew" id="ID_SUB_RACE_SCHOLAR">
		<supports>Evnir</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Always curious and always willing to listen, Scholar Evnir are always out the hunt for new knowledge and new things to discover. They love to delve into the knowledge of the land they've woken up in and investigating the different stories and legends that the people of the land have, taking special care to find the honest roots of stories and artifacts. Despite their nature of enjoying learning, they also enjoy discovering things as well, often wandering freely to do research on whatever they're working on, fearlessly exploring ruins and ancient temples to find whatever clues they can.
 .</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Wisdom or Intelligence score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Naturally Curious.</em></strong> You are proficient in the Investigation skill.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Keen Mind.</em></strong> You always know which way is North. You always know the number of hours left before the next sunrise or sunset. You can accurately recall anything you have seen or heard within the past month.</p>
			
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="height" modifier="1d20">4'6"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="1d4">300 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase (Scholar)" supports="ID_INTERNAL_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_INTERNAL_ASI_WISDOM" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_NATURALLY_CURIOUS" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KEEN_MIND" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Naturally Curious" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_NATURALLY_CURIOUS">
		<description>
			<p>You are proficient in the Investigation skill.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You are proficient in the Investigation skill.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Keen Mind" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KEEN_MIND">
		<description>
			<p>You always know which way is North. You always know the number of hours left before the next sunrise or sunset. You can accurately recall anything you have seen or heard within the past month.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You always know which way is North. You can tell how many hours before next sunrise or sunset. You can accurately remember anything seen or heard from the past month.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
		<element name="Pathfinder" type="Sub Race" source="Homebrew" id="ID_SUB_RACE_PATHFINDER">
		<supports>Evnir</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Knowing that a path needs to be cut through the wilderness, these Evnir are always out at the front, blazing new trails and watching for dangers that could arise along the way. Unlike the rest of their kind, their gear make up lets them move quietly, not having to worry about the usual noise of gears and springs clicking and moving inside of them, possibly giving away their position, letting them hide and observe without the fear of being detected as easily. While still open and friendly like the rest of their kind, but always seeming to be on the watch for what is to come.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Dexterity score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Silent Running.</em></strong> Your internal make up runs quieter now. Your Dexterity (Stealth) checks are no longer done at a disadvantage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Path Clearer.</em></strong> Difficult terrain doesn't slow your group's travel and you cannot become lost except by magical means.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="height" modifier="1d20">4'6"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="1d4">300 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SILENT_RUNNING" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_PATH_CLEARER" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Silent Running" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SILENT_RUNNING">
		<description>
			<p>Your internal make up runs quieter now. Your Dexterity (Stealth) checks are no longer done at a disadvantage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Your Dexterity (Stealth) checks are no longer done at a disadvantage.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="innate speed" value="35" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Path Clearer" type="Racial Trait" source="Homebrew" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_PATH_CLEARER">
		<description>
			<p>Difficult terrain doesn't slow your group's travel and you cannot become lost except by magical means.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Difficult terrain doesn't slow your group's travel and you cannot become lost except by magical means.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>
